‘Time waits for no man’ – or so the saying goes.
常言道，“岁月不待人”。
We can’t stop time and we can’t control it, although sometimes, in our minds, we think time flies – for example, when the weekend arrives, we feel it’s over in no time!
我们既无法让时间停下脚步，也不能掌控它的流逝，不过有时候在我们的感觉里，时间过得飞快——比如周末明明刚到，转眼就结束了！
But if this year in particular feels like it’s passing more quickly than others have done, there could be a scientific explanation why.
但如果你觉得今年的时光流逝得格外快，这背后或许有科学的解释。
Of course, we know a year is usually 365 days long.
我们当然都知道，一年通常有365天。
Clever scientists calculated this a long time ago.
很久以前，聪慧的科学家们就算出了这个结果。
They also worked out that every four years, we need an extra day to keep our calendar in sync – this is called a leap year.
他们还发现，每四年我们需要额外增加一天，才能让日历与地球公转周期保持同步——这一年被称为闰年。
But 2021 isn’t one of those years, and yet it’s not behaving like a normal year.
但2021年不是闰年，然而它异于往常。
Scientists and astrophysicists have done the math and discovered the Earth is moving faster than it ever has in the last 50 years.
科学家和天体物理学家经过计算发现，地球的自转速度达到了过去50年来的最快水平。
This means that 2021 is going to be the shortest year in decades.
这意味着2021年将成为几十年来最短的一年。
Apparently, this is because the Earth is spinning faster on its axis, quicker than it has done in decades, and the days are therefore shorter.
显然，这是因为地球绕地轴的自转速度创下了数十年以来的新高，所以每一天的时长都变短了。
But they are only short by a tiny amount – around 0.05 milliseconds – so don’t panic if you haven’t noticed!
不过这种缩短的幅度极小，大约只有0.05毫秒，所以就算你毫无察觉也不必惊慌！
However, long-term these milliseconds add up.
但从长远来看，这些毫秒的差距会不断累积。
Astrophysicist Graham Jones and Konstantin Bikos from Time and Date told The Independent newspaper: “If the Earth’s rotation continues to quicken, we may at some point require a negative leap second.
时间与日期网站的天体物理学家格雷厄姆·琼斯和康斯坦丁·比科斯在接受《独立报》采访时表示：“如果地球自转速度持续加快，未来某一天我们或许需要引入负闰秒。
If this happens, our clocks would skip a second in order to keep up with the hurrying Earth.”
一旦实施负闰秒，为了跟上地球的自转节奏，我们的时钟就要跳过一秒钟。”
Since 1972, 27 leap seconds have only been added to our time and none have been taken away.
自1972年以来，人类只给时间增加过27次闰秒，从未减少过一秒。
This really is only of concern for atomic clocks – the most accurate timekeeping devices in history.
这件事其实只关乎原子钟——这种有史以来最精准的计时工具。
Studying the Earth’s rotation and then subtracting or adding a leap second to these clocks can ensure they remain aligned and keep us on time.
通过监测地球自转，并相应地给原子钟增减闰秒，就能确保它们与地球自转保持同步，让我们的时间始终准确无误。
But now, maybe we need to get a move on before this ‘shorter’ year is gone in a split second!
不过话说回来，或许我们得抓紧时间行动起来，免得这“更短”的一年一眨眼就过去了！